大家还记得第1节课中的这张图吗？  适配器
Do you remember this diagram from lesson one? The adapter
有一个指向原始数据的引用  另外还有
has a reference to the raw data. And has instructions on
如何创建每一个列表项布局的方法  这些布局最终
how to build each list item layout. These layouts eventually make
会组成这里的ListView控件  但是如果这里的任何一项数据改变了
it into the ListView here. But what happens if any
会发生什么呢  让我们来举个例子  现在有第四个
of this data changes. Let's say for example, there's a fourth
联系人叫Don  适配器知道如何为Don创建一个
contact named Don. The adapter knows how to create a list
列表项布局  但是现在的ListView控件的数据是过时的
item layout for Don. But now the ListView is outdated
因为它只有3个列表项  不管怎样  我们需要适配器
because it only has three items. Somehow, we need the adapter
来通知ListView控件数据发生了变化
to notify the ListView that things have
幸运的是  有一个叫
changed. And lucky for us, there's a method
adapter.notifyDataSetChanged()的方法  这个方法通知所有附加的观察者
called: adapter.notifyDataSetChanged(). This notifies any attached observers,
比如这个  依赖的适配器数据发生了变化
like this one, that the underlying adapter data has
这个时候ListView控件需要再次计算
changed. Then the ListView needs to populate
它的列表项  所以它问适配器
its children again. So it asks the adapter
有多少列表项  适配器回答说
how many items there are? And the adapter
有4个  然后ListView控件会逐个获取
responds with four. Then the ListView goes and fetches
每一个列表项直到它自己填满屏幕
each one individually until it fills up the screen.
ListView控件是通过这个方法
And it's through that method that the ListView is able
获取它所有的列表项的  但是现在
to get all its list items. But now you
你肯定在想  我们确实成功地更新了ListView控件
must be thinking. How did we actually update the ListView
但是我们并没有在app中添加这行代码呀
successfully, without adding this line of code in our
其实呢  在使用ArrayAdapter的时候  无论何时你向它添加
app? Well, with ArrayAdapter, whenever you add or
或者移除元素  它自动在内部调用了notifyDataSetChanged()方法  也就是说
remove elements from it, it internally calls notifyDataSetChanged(). That means
我们不需要做任何事情  但是我们如何确认这一点呢
we don't have to do anything. But how can be
我们可以查看一下ArrayAdapter类
confirm this? Well, we can check the actual implementation
在framework中的实现  这里就是
of the ArrayAdapter class in the framework. And here's
ArrayAdapter类在Android的framework层中的代码
the code for the ArrayAdapter class within the Android
你可以点击下面的链接来继续查看详细代码
framework. You can follow along with the link below.
首先我们来找一下add()方法  记住
First, we're going to search for the add() method. Remember,
我们之前就是用这个方法向适配器中添加天气预报的字符串的
we added forecast strings to the adapter using this
并且我们可以确认的是
method. And sure enough we see that, the
notifyDataSetChanged()方法在内部被调用了
notifyDataSetChanged() method is called internally. But you
但是你可能在想这里的这个布尔型变量是做什么的
might be thinking what about this Boolean here. Well
让我们来把它找出来  如果你滑动到最上面
let's look it up. If you scroll to the top
你会看到mNotifyOnChange变量一开始
you'll see that, mNotifyOnChange is declared as
是被声明为true的  如果你查看它在其它地方的使用会发现
true initially. As you go through your other references you'll
它只在这个叫setNotifyOnChange()的方法里
see that it's only changed here in this
被改变了  因为我们不会通过参数false
setNotifyOnChange() method. Since we don't call this public
调用这个公共方法  那么每次适配器更新的时候
method with the value false, then we know that we're
我们都会被安全地通知到
going to be safely notified each time the adapter updates.
现在再让我们回到add()方法  我想给你们
Now let's go back to the add() method. I want to
再看一件事情  你会注意到
show you one more thing. You'll notice in the
在addAll()方法中  它只通知它的观察者一次  然而
addAll() method, it only notifies its observers once. Whereas in
对于add()方法每次你调用它  它都会更新它的
the add() method every time you call this it will update
观察者们  这表明我们的代码每次调用add()方法都在
it's observers. That means that our code actually is refreshing
刷新列表  因此  如果你的目标设备是运行Honeycomb或者更新的系统
the list every time. So, if you're targeting Honeycomb or above
你可以使用这个方法来提高一点效率
you can use this method to be a little more
总之  不要害怕尝试自己去做这些事情
efficient. In general don't be afraid to try and do this
小窍门  任何时候如果你对某件事不确定
on your own. As a general pro tip, if you're ever unsure about something,
尽情地去查看
feel free to go and check the
Android源代码吧  不要把framework层的代码想象成
Android source code. Don't treat the framework code
是一个黑盒子  充分利用Android开源的优势
like a black box. Take advantage of the fact that Android is open source. The
你越了解这个平台
more you learn about the platform the
你就会成为一个越好的Android开发者
better of an Android developer you can become.